A Guide to The Potomac Conservancy, Inc., Conservation easement case files, 1993-2009 [ongoing]
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
The Potomac Conservancy, Inc., Conservation easement case files 1933-2009 [ongoing]
Library of Virginia
42530
1.45 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The entire collection is filed under Accession 42530.
Gift of The Potomac Conservancy, Inc., Winchester, Virgina, 24 February 2006. (Acc. 42530)
Gift of The Potomac Conservancy, Inc., Winchester, Virginia, additions, 31 March 2008. (Acc. 43689)
Gift of The Potomac Conservancy, Inc., Winchester, Virginia, additions, 29 Septembetr 2009. (Acc. 44543)
Biographical/Historical Information
The Potomac Conservancy conducts a comprehensive land protection program across four states and the District of Columbia. Protecting forests, wetlands, farmlands, and other valuable open space is the central focus of the Conservancy's work. To this end, the organization has developed and implemented a variety of land and water restoration projects.
As a member of the Potomac Land Trust Network, a collaborative affiliation of land trusts and conservation organizations working to protect land throughout the watershed, The Conservancy promotes cooperation and resource-sharing among partners to achieve the common goal of a healthy Potomac River and healthy watershed communities. In addition, it provides counseling and other conservation support services for more than seventy other land trusts.
The Potomac Conservancy offers hands-on volunteer and education programs for adults and young people to foster a stewardship ethic and creating a community of river stewards dedicated to protecting the natural, scenic, historic, and recreational qualities of the Potomac River.
The Conservancy also partners with other land trusts, conservation organizations, and local, state, and federal agencies to more efficiently and expeditiously achieve land protection and restoration goals. With the goal to achieve healthy, diverse forests and grasslands; clean, clear water in abundant supply; a balance of open space and urban growth; and a satisfying quality of life for all residents, The Potomac Conservancy serves as the lead partner in The Potomac Watershed Partnership,a large-scale land restoration and protection effort focused on the Antietam and Monocacy watersheds in Maryland and Virginia's Shenandoah watershed.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of conservation easement case files compiled by The Potomac Conservancy, Inc. Each file concerns a specific landowner and contains a baseline report. This report includes a copy of the Deed of Easement, as well as photographs/slides, maps, and a detailed written description of the property.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by date of easement.
Contents List
- Marie W. Ridder Living Trust - McLean, VA 10/13/1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cox, Joya - McLean, VA (1 of 2) 6/1/2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cox, Joya - McLean, VA (2 of 2) 6/1/2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Foster, Wes and Betty - McLean, VA 12/21/2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mardirosian, Aram and Johanna - McLean, VA 12/27/2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Horwitz, Michael and Marcus, Devra - McLean, VA 12/27/2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Stockton, Peter and Brian, Danielle - Leesburg, VA 4/30/2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Segall-Bumbaugh Property - Arlington, VA 12/21/2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Blueridge Center for Environmental Stewardship - Loudoun Co., VA (1 of 2) 9/30/2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Blue Ridge Center for Environmental Stewardship - Loudoun Co., VA (2 of 2) 9/30/2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Wise Property - Ashburn, VA 12/8/2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Garms Property - Toms Brook, VA 12/23/2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- McCann-Slaughter Property - Winchester, VA 3/9/2005 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mount Pleasant Farm - Strasburg, VA 7/11/2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Gavitt Property - Frederick Co., VA 11/1/2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Salamander Easement - Middleburg, Loudoun Co., VA 11/1/2007 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
- Trott Property - Fort Valley, Shenandoah Co., VA 12/17/2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Marlboro Angus: Snapp Farm - Frederick Co., VA 2/26/2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Finger Lakes property - Frederick Co., VA 12/3/2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Green property - Frederick Co., VA 12/5/2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Royal property - Frederick Co., VA 12/5/2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Snapp farm (property of Elizabeth "Betty" Snapp) - Frederick Co., VA 6/29/2009 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Oversize Maps [6 sheets] 2000-2003 (Map-case 6, Drawer 7)